JEREMIAH SILVA

Calgary, AB T3H 2L2 (587) 434-3195

<u>ieremiah.ca9@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/jeremiah-silva</u> <u>github.com/Jeremiah-Silva</u>

Bs. Social Communication. I am a full-stack developer with a passion for coding and learning about the latest technologies and for helping develop a wide variety of features including both frontend and backend components. Over one year of hands-on experience including Python, SQL, MySQL, JavaScript, Vue.js, and React.js. Eager to develop skills in a fast-paced environment and contribute to the success of a company.

EDUCATION

2003-2008 Bs. Social Communication

Center University of Belo Horizonte, Brazil.

2015 Degree certified by IQAS.

WORK EXPERIENCE RELEVANT

Full Stack Developer Internship

2022 Inception, Calgary

- Acted as Front-end developer implementing React-based applications such as new navigation features, scheduling systems employees, and card readers, hook form submit for one WINK Technologies software company for opticians and optometrists.
- Developing for Calgary City Farmstand eCommerce web app with Javascript and SQL database.
- Acted as Back-end developer adding API integration in payment gateway Python.
- Participated in the daily stand-up meeting to track the progress of the sprint backlog in Agile Scrum Squads using Jira.
- Proficient understanding of code versioning tools, such as Git Hub or Bit Bucket.

Warehousing Leader

2017-2021 Parts Canada Distributor, Calgary

- Received, stored, and distributed material, tools, equipment, and supplies throughout the warehouse to sustain production activities (reconcile, pick, unload, label and store).
- Unloaded trucks, checked in merchandise, reconciled purchase orders with sales orders, and distribute received inventory to designated production areas.
- Prepared and completed orders for delivery or pick up according to schedule (pick, load, pack, wrap, label, stage, and ship).
- Facilitated inventory management and inform management of low inventory, recorded inventory counts in computer systems.

JEREMIAH SILVA

Calgary, AB T3H 2L2 (587) 434-3195

<u>ieremiah.ca9@gmail.com</u> <u>linkedin.com/in/jeremiah-silva</u> github.com/Jeremiah-Silva

Customer Service Representative

2015-2016 Paysafe Digital Wallet, Calgary

- Provided information about the products and services.
- Troubleshoot and resolve product issues and concerns.
- Document and update customer records based on interactions.
- Worked in a cross-functional team to develop strategies to increase customer service levels.

Website Designer

2014-2012 Mutari Health & Beauty Company, Brazil

- Optimized the site for maximum speed and scalability
- Ensured website function and stability across desktop and mobile.
- Designed engaging and responsive landing pages

UX/UI Designer

2008-2014 Eighth Presbyterian Church, Brazil

- Contributed during the project specification and requirement gathering phase.
- Wrote reusable code blocks and finish the coding within the stipulated time.
- Collaborated with back-end developers for integration of the application.
- Turned UI/UX designs into prototypes, creating excellent interactions from designs by using Figma.

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

2022 - InceptionU Calgary

(Full Stack Developer Full-Time project-based learning 6-month course)

2022 - Free Code Camp

- JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures.
- Relational Database
- Front End Development Libraries.
- Back End Development and APIs.

2021/22 – Udemy Certifications

- Bootcamp 2022: Full Stack Web Developer Bootcamp.
- Frameworks: ReactJS, Redux, React Native, AngularJS, VueJs.
- Front End: JavaScript, HTML and CSS.
- Object-Oriented-Programming languages: Python, PHP, TypeScript.
- Server side: ExpressJS, NodeJS.
- Agile Methodology and Software Development Life Cycle.
- Database: No SQL Mongo, MS SQL, My SQL.
- Mobile phone development using React Native